Guide to the Francis Warrington Dawson Family Papers, 1386-1963, bulk 1859-1950 RL.10147
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings, 1
  - Dawson Family Writings, 1
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Journals, 1898-1908; 4 folders (Box 34)
      Manuscript. Journals contain miscellaneous jottings concerning girlhood memories, visits to mediums and other supernatural phenomena, Charleston gossip, and experiences abroad. The first journal, untitled, begins August 13, 1898. The second journal, titled "As It Was Spoken: Notes by the Way," begins August 6, 1906. The third journal, called "As It Was Told," begins July 1907. The fourth journal, also untitled, begins July 24, 1908.
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Comment on the Role of Women as Childbearers, undated (Box 35)
      Manuscript. Contains original and photocopy to preserve fragile manuscript.
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Diaries, 1862-1865; 6 folders (Box 35)
      Manuscript. Six-volume diary, parts of which appeared posthumously as "A Confederate Girl's Diary." Volume 1 begins 1862 Jan. 10-1862 June 16. Volume 2 1862 June 16-1862 Aug. 3. Volume 3 1862 Aug. 4-1863 Jan. 4. Volume 4 1863 Jan. 15-1863 Aug. 7. Volume 5 1863 Aug. 14-1865 June 15. Volume 6 begins 1865 July 4. Many of the diaries have later entries and notes dating from 1866-1896. Volume 6 also includes photocopy.
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. A Confederate Girl's Diary - Extracts, undated; 2 folders (Box 35)
      Typescript. A number of extracts from Sarah Morgan Dawson's diaries. One folder of press clippings pertaining to its publication.
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. The Ghost of a Sunbonnet, etc., undated (Box 35)
      Typescript. Several titles published in different sources bound together. Titles include "The Ghost of a Sunbonnet," "Me Auntie Own Silk Umbrella," and "A Midsummer Madness."
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. In the Wilds of Tennessee, undated (Box 35)
      Typescript with edits.
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Biography of Francis Warrington Dawson, 1897 (Box 35)
      Manuscript. Note at beginning stating it was "Written for Cyclopaedia Put. Co." in Boston, Mass.
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Biograhical Sketch of Francis Warrington Dawson, 1894 (Box 35)
      Typescript. Written at request of J.T. White for the National Cyclopedia of American Biography. Revised by Warrington Dawson. Also includes Warrington Dawson's comments on the sketch.
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. The Narrative of Sarah Morgan Dawson, 1890-1894; 1949; 2 folders (Box 36)
      Manuscript. 2 volumes. "For Ethel and Warrington. I make a memorandum of the last day your dear father spent on earth [...]." Accompanied by memo written by Warrington Dawson giving further information on the narrative (dated 1949 Feb. 9).
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Sounding Brass and Tinkling Cymbals, undated (Box 36)
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Une Grande Dame of the 18th Century, undated; 6 folders (Box 36)
      Manuscript. Title page notes: "Compilation of the Memoirs of La Marquise de Crequy 1700-1803."
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. Statement of the Question Between General Siegling and Myself, 1890 Feb. 4 (Box 36)
      Manuscript and typescript. Includes note from Warrington Dawson, dated June 6, 1959, giving further details to the narrative.
    - Dawson, Sarah Morgan. "Madam: Extracts from the correspondence of Madame, duchess d'Orleans, Charlotte Elizabeth of Bavaria, mother of the regent of France., undated; 2 boxes (Box 37-38)
      Manuscript. 2 volumes. Extracts made by Sarah Morgan Dawson from the correspondence of Madame, Duchesse d'Orleans, Charlotte Elizabeth of Bavaria, mother of the Regent of France.
    - Dawson, Warrington. 13 Years ---- 13 Windows, undated; 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Dawson, Warrington. $1000, undated (Box 39)
    - Dawson, Warrington. 1946, undated (Box 39)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Address Book, undated (Box 39)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Admiral de Grasse at Yorktown (Bulletin No. 14), 1931 (Box 39)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Adventures in Diplomacy and Journalism: The True Story of Oscar and Eve: Why I Adopted Them, 1940 (Box 39)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Adventures in the Night, 1919, undated; 3 folders (Box 39, 64)
      Typescript with notes to printer.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Almayer's Folly, undated (Box 64)
      Manuscript fragments.
    - Dawson, Warrington. At Neptune's Gates: Extracts from the Private Record-Books of a Sedentary Diplomat in Versailles, 1934-1945, undated; 3 folders (Box 39)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Autobiographical Sketch], undated (Box 62)
      Manuscript. French.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Les Aventures de Buz et Fury, undated; 2 folders (Box 39)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Africa: Miscellaneous Notes and Excerpts, undated (Box 39)
      Manuscript and typescript. Miscellaneous notes and excerpts on Africa.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Arrow of Love, 1891-1892 (Box 39)
      Manuscript. Handwritten note from Warrington Dawson describing the play, written when he was twelve and thirteen.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Arrow of Love, 1897 (Box 40)
      Manuscript. "From the original manuscript. Copied verbatim in 1897."
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Art of America (Lecture), undated (Box 40)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Atmosphere and Theodore Roosevelt, undated (Box 40)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Auguste Rodin - Articles, undated (Box 40)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Auguste Rodin's L'art, undated (Box 40)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Auguste Rodin - Notes, 1898-1911 (Box 40)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Auguste Rodin's Notes on Life, Art, and Nature. Collected and Translated by Warrington Dawson., undated; 2 folders (Box 40)
      Typescript. Copy 2 has a note with more information about the text. Contains partial third copy.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Notes on Life and Art, draft, undated; 3 folders (Box 40)
    - Dawson, Warrington. La Balafre, undated (Box 40)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Beatification of Joan of Arc, 1909 March 21 (Box 40)
      Manuscript, typescript. Lecture given at St. Germaine's club.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Beaumains, undated (Box 40)
      Manuscript of play. Also includes program from production of the play.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Blinks's Ghost, 1896 (Box 40)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Border Lines: A Novel of Africa, undated; 6 folders (Box 40)
      Typescript. Accompanied by note signed by Warrington Dawson on 1941 July 12 with information about status of novel.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Bowker Case, undated (Box 41)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Le Caractère Spécial de la Musique Nègre en Amérique, 1932 (Box 41)
      Typescript. Offprint.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Chevalier d'Ancteville and his Journal of "The Chesapeake Campaign", undated (Box 41)
      Typescript with handwritten note by Warrington Dawson giving further information.
    - Dawson, Warrington. A Confederate Girl's Diary: Introduction, 1913 (Box 41)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Consequences of a Grudge, 1895; 3 folders (Box 41)
      Manuscript. 3 bound volumes.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Consequences of a Grudge, 1896 (Box 41)
      Part typescript and part manuscript.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Corpse in the Curtain, 1941, undated (Box 41)
      Manuscript and typescript. Various drafts and proofs with edits.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Cross Channel Tunnel, undated (Box 41)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Crossroads, undated; 2 folders (Box 41, 64)
      Typescript. Accompanied by typewritten note about circumstances of its creation. Manuscript in oversize.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Crystal Screen, undated (Box 41)
      Manuscript. Draft of Part I. Original title (The Unseen) crossed out.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Crystal Screen, undated; 3 folders (Box 41)
      Manuscript. Full draft with some typescript edits.
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Defense of Roosevelt's Hunting] (Box 41)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Demolishers (?), 1930 April 17 (Box 41)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Deux grandes ames...], undated (Box 42)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Diary, 1905-1911 (Box 42)
      Manuscript. Labeled Volume I. Collection of thoughts and reminiscences in French and English.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Diary, 1909 (Box 42)
      Manuscript. Lett's Scribbling Diary with daily entries. Short descriptions of what happened on particular days.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Diary, 1928-1929 (Box 42)
      Manuscript with dated entries.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Diary Extracts, 1946 (Box 42)
      Typescript. Miscellaneous entries.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Le Don de Paul Clermont, undated; 4 folders (Box 42, 64)
      Manuscript. 2 bound volumes and 1 looseleaf manuscript. Looseleaf housed in oversize.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The East Africans, undated (Box 42)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Essential Stories by Men and Women of Note, undated; 2 folders (Box 42)
      Typescript. Full title: Essential Stories of Men and Women of Note: H. de Balzac, W.M. Thackeray, Theodore Roosevelt, Sarah Morgan Dawson, A. de Musset, Grace King, Maria Edgeworth, E. Rey, Sir Walter Scott, Vance Thompson, Voltaire. Transcribed and translated by Warrington Dawson. With Remarks of his Own.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Fanciful Child, undated (Box 42)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Flight Escape, undated; 3 folders (Box 43)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Les Francais Morts pour l'Independance Americaine et la Reconstruction Historique de Williamsburg, 1931; 3 folders (Box 43)
      Typescript with edits. 3 copies. Copy 2 and 3 fragmentary.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Les Francais Morts [draft], undated (Box 43)
      Typescript with edits. Contains Chapter 5 "Camps de Prisonnieres."
    - Dawson, Warrington. [The French literary elite...], undated (Box 43)
    - Dawson, Warrington. French Society under the Third Republic, undated (Box 43)
      Manuscript. 2 copies.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Fresh Air Art Society., undated (Box 43)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Fugit Amor, undated (Box 43)
      Typescript with edits. Extract from the News and Courier.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Un Garde Suisse de Louis XVI au Service de l'Amerique: Le baron Gaspard de Gallatin, 1931; 2 folders (Box 43)
      Typescript and manuscript.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Garett's Boat, 1923 Jan. 19 (Box 43)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Gallatin Narrative] With Rochambeau's Army in America, undated (Box 43)
      Typescript. Translated by Warrington Dawson.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Ghosts and Whimsies, undated (Box 43)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Gift of Paul Clermont, 1915-1916 (Box 61)
      Manuscript. 2 bound oversize volumes. Inlaid in volume one is a typescript of Rudyard Kipling's opinion of the piece.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Gift of Paul Clermont, 1939 (Box 43)
      Typescript. Fragment. Accompanied by note from Warrington Dawson.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Golden Part, undated; 4 folders (Box 44)
      Manuscript. 4 bound volumes
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Golden Part, undated; 3 folders (Box 44)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Grain Judging, undated (Box 44)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Grand Elixir: A Novel of Two Parts, undated; 4 folders (Box 64)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Grand Marshal Bertrand's "Cahiers de Sainte Helene": A Hitherto Unpublished Contemporary Record of the Last Days of Napoleon Bonaparte at St Helena, 1950 (Box 44)
    - Dawson, Warrington. A Great Contemporary: Joseph Conrad, undated (Box 44)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Guardian Demons, undated (Box 64)
      Typescript. Page proofs and dust jacket proof.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Historical Significance of Yorktown, 1931 (Box 44)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The History of My Birds, 1929 (Box 44)
      Manuscript. Note on first page: "Begun January 6, 1929. Based on my diary...."
    - Dawson, Warrington. Honeymoon, undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. In Folsam's Bungalow, undated (Box 45)
      Typescript. 3 Copies.
    - Dawson, Warrington. In Memoriam: Mary Walker Barney, 1893 (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Irrigation, undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Ismailiah], undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. J. Kerslake Thomas, undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Joffre's Conditions for Armistice, undated (Box 45)
      Manuscript. French. Accompanied by English note.
    - Dawson, Warrington. John Boyes, undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Joseph Conrad, undated (Box 45)
      Typescript. Part of article?
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Joseph Conrad Article], 1917 Feb 2 (Box 64)
      Manuscript. Appeared in the New York Times.
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Joseph Conrad Lecture], 1912 March 3 (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Joseph Conrad Notes], undated; 2 folders (Box 45, 64)
    - Dawson, Warrington. A Joseph Conrad Reminiscence, undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Journal of Pierre Durousseau de Fayolle, undated; 2 folders (Box 45)
      Manuscript and typescript.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Journalisme Americain, 1907 (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Kipling, undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Lake Naivasha Monster, undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Land of Sleep and Death, undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Lectures by Warrington Dawson, undated (Box 45)
      Typescript. List of lectures given by Warrington Dawson with short descriptions.
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Literary Notes], undated (Box 65)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Living Art: A Novel of Paris, undated; 7 folders (Box 62)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Lone Wolf, undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Looseleaf Diary], 1918-1919 (Box 45)
      Manuscript. A number of the entries are labeled confidential or confidential report.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Lost, Strayed, or Stolen: Fourteen Cannon. An Episode of the American Revolution, undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Major Jean La Boularderie de Treville, undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Man Who Faced the Truth: A Play in One Act, undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Man Who Wouldn't Be Dead, undated (Box 45)
      Manuscript. Accompanied by note.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Man Who Wouldn't Be Dead, undated; 4 folders (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Manor of the Court of France, 1919 April 27; 3 folders (Box 65)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Masai Lion Hunt, undated (Box 45)
      Typescript. Also contains manuscript notes related to the subject.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Medusa's Sisters, undated (Box 45)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Mes Journees a la Chancelierie, undated (Box 46)
      Typescript. 4 Copies.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Messina Statement from Theodore Roosevelt, 1909 Apr. (Box 46)
      Typescript. Dawson transcribed a statement from Roosevelt from memory. Accompanied by note with explanation.
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Miller's Materialisations], undated (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Mirror of the Sea, undated (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Mission of Art, undated (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Mistaken Engagement, 1895 (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Modern French Drama & Plays for Children, 1913 (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. My Good Friends Ted, Kermit, and Archie Roosevelt, undated (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. My Experiences (War Diary), 1914-1918; 3 folders (Box 46)
      Manuscript. 5 volumes.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Napoleon's "Pensionnat de la Legion d'Honneur" at Ecouen, undated (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Natives, undated (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Le Negre aux Etats-Unis, undated (Box 46)
      Typescript. Page proofs.
    - Dawson, Warrington. A New Record of the Sieges of Yorktown and Pensacola, undated (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The News that Wasn't, undated (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Note Confidentielle: Travaux Municipaux de Versailles, 23 Nov. 1938 (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Notebook], 1885-1895 (Box 46)
      Manuscript. Filled with poetry, prose, and speeches (including one reminiscing about his father in 1895). Page 41 notes that the rest of the entries were copied in 1896 (originals lost) but the original dates were kept.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Novel of George, 1913; 5 folders (Box 63)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Des Oeuvres d'art (Lecture), undated (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. A Onze Heures: Drame en I acte, undated (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Opportunity and Theodore Roosevelt, 1923; 3 folders (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Opportunity and Theodore Roosevelt (Memorandum Concerning), undated (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Opportunity and Theodore Roosevelt (Reviews), undated (Box 46)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Outfitting Safaris], undated (Box 47)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Le Parfait Commis, undated (Box 47)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Paul Clement's Story and My Own, undated (Box 47)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Peculiar Happening at Mrs. Montressor's Dinner-Party, undated (Box 47)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Poetry], undated (Box 47)
      Manuscript and typescript. Miscellaneous poems by Warrington Dawson.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Power Named Jules: A Psychic Experience, undated (Box 47)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Practical French of the Third Republic, undated (Box 47)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Press Clippings], undated (Box 47)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Purser's Shilling: A Very Modern Sea Story, undated (Box 47)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Pyramid, 1910-1921, undated; 10 folders (Box 47-48)
      Typescript fragmented draft. Some manuscript notes. Manuscript version of chapter 12, "The Learning of Life." One folder of page proofs (excerpts) with various pages glued to larger pieces of paper. Final folder contains manuscript draft, noting that it was begun the 2nd of May, 1910 and completed the 28th of March, 1921.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Rains & Crops, undated (Box 48)
    - Dawson, Warrington. La Reconstruction Historique de Williamsburg, 1930 (Box 48)
      Typescript. Offprint. 3 copies.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Refugee: The Experience of a War Correspondent, undated (Box 48)
      Typescript. Ripped from original source.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Region of Sleep and Death, undated (Box 48)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Reminiscences, 1914-1918 (Box 48)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Requisc--cat: A Play in One Act, undated (Box 48)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Rock, 1909-1920; 5 folders (Box 65)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Roosevelt: Hunter and Moon, undated (Box 48)
      Typescript. Transcript of lecture given by Warrington Dawson including introductory remarks.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Roosevelt's Kijabe Mission Speech, undated (Box 48)
      Typescript. Dawson's report on speech with excerpt.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Roosevelt Log: British East Africa, 1909, 7 folders (Box 48)
      Typescript draft and manuscript fragments.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Une Rose de l'Ile de France, undated (Box 48)
      Typescript. Play in one act.
    - Dawson, Warrington. La Société de l'Art Francais, 1947 (Box 48)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Scar: A Novel of the South, 1903-1906, 1950; 11 folders (Box 48-49, 66)
      Manuscript and typescript revising manuscript version. Typescript accompanied by letter (in French) giving over translation rights. One folder of typewritten draft fragments. Incomplete French translation in oversize.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Scar and the Scum: Novels of the South, undated (Box 49)
      Typescript and manuscript. Note on title page: "A New Edition Set Up From The Original Manuscripts With Formerly Suppressed Passages Now For The First Time Published And A Preface By The Author.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Scourge, undated; 9 folders (Box 49-50)
      Manuscript and typescript. Manuscript titled "The Scum." Typescript titled "The Scourge."
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Scum, 1905, undated; 7 folders (Box 50)
      Manuscript and typescript. Included is a bound manuscript with note from Warrington Dawson on the forced changes to his novel and the importance of these.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Sea Diary, 1898 (Box 51)
      Manuscript. Includes inserted memorabilia.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Secret Sharer; Outpost of Progress; Karain, undated (Box 51)
      Typescript. One document containing three separately-titled short pieces.
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Sheet Music], undated (Box 65)
      Manuscript. Also contains handwritten notes.
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Short Essays], undated (Box 51)
      Manuscript. Titles include: "On a Fiction," "On Matter," "On Accidental Lying," "On Discoveries," "On Doing Things," "On Positiveness," "On Using Slang," and "On Interpretations."
    - Dawson, Warrington. Sibylla, 1910-1925; 4 folders (Box 51)
      Manuscript. 3 bound volumes. Looseleaf manuscript in oversize.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Sin: An Allegory of the Truth, 1912; 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Sleeping Sickness], undated (Box 51)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Southern Negro, 1911 Feb. 12 (Box 51)
      Typescript. Lecture given at St. Germaine's Club.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Spirit of Pershing's Army, undated (Box 51)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Stigand-Kikuyus, undated; 2 folders (Box 51, 66)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Stigand-Safari, undated (Box 51)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Stigand-Swahilis, undated; 2 folders (Box 51, 66)
      Manuscript
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Storm, undated (Box 51)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Strange Guests for Dinner: A Play in One Act, undated (Box 51)
      Typescript. Accompanied by letters asking for production consideration.
    - Dawson, Warrington. The Successful Honest Man: A Play in Five Scenes, undated (Box 51)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Suez Canal, undated (Box 51)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Summaries], undated; 2 folders (Box 51)
      Typescript. Summaries of the following texts: "Three Days: A Confession by Thad Wrenson," "The Ghost of a Chance," "Return," "The Cat Woman," "The Amateur Ambassador," "The Corpse in the Curtain," and "Border Lines."
    - Dawson, Warrington. Tales of Unrest, undated (Box 51)
      Manuscript. Fragment.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Texas Duel: A Novel by Warrington Dawson, undated; 8 folders (Box 52)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Thad, undated; 5 folders (Box 52-53)
      Manuscript. Accompanied by summary. Thad's Three Days: A Confession.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Theodore Roosevelt: Realist, undated; 2 folders (Box 53)
      Manuscript. Foreword: Making Much of Things. Also includes miscellaneous notes and outlines.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Theatre Scout, 1936-37 (Box 53)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Think It Not Strange: Reminiscences 1914-1959 (Box 53)
      Typescript. Accompanied by note with short summary and reasons for not seeking publication.
    - Dawson, Warrington. T.R. - Oyster Bay 1913 (Box 53)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [Transcripts of Conversations with Theodore Roosevelt], 1921, 1923 (Box 53)
      Manuscript. Written down from memory. Dated 1921 Dec. 19 and 1923 July 19.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Trilliums, 1910; 3 folders (Box 63)
    - Dawson, Warrington. A Trip Round Lake Victoria Nyanza and to Uganda Towns, undated (Box 53)
    - Dawson, Warrington. The True Dimension, 1914; 4 folders (Box 66)
    - Dawson, Warrington. [This Case of Pickpocket Journalism], undated (Box 53)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Uganda, undated (Box 53)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Uganda Up to Date, 1912 (Box 53)
      Manuscript of lecture and typescript of reviews. Given at the Lyceum Club in Paris, on 26th June, 1912.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Undiplomatic Recollections: 1898-1938, undated (Box 53)
    - Dawson, Warrington. Unknown Versailles, undated (Box 53)
    - Dawson, Warrington. University School: Richmond, Virginia, 1895-1913 (Box 53)
      Manuscript. Begun 12 October 1895. Mix of journal entries and creative writing in English and French.
    - Dawson, Warrington. Vengeance Cast Away, undated (Box 53)